A Guide to the Settlers Museum of Southwest Virginia Records, 1988-2006
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Settlers Museum of Southwest Virginia Records 1988-2006
Special Collections, Kegley Library
2010.16
32 folders.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Mary B. Kegley in 2010 as part of the Mary B. Kegley Collection.
Scope and Content
The collection of 32 folders consists of board meeting documents, correspondence, reports, and newspaper clippings relating to the development and operation of the Settlers Museum of Southwest Virginia. Founded by Charles Phillippi in 1987, the Museum seeks to portray 19th century frontier life via exhibits and a working farm and schoolhouse. Exhibits also include the story of the migration of Scots-Irish and German settlers from Pennsylvania, down the Great Road, into the region. While Charles Phillippi died in 2005, the Museum continues operation during the spring, summer, and fall. The collection here consists of documents collected by Mary B. Kegley during her tenure as consultant and Board member.
Contents List
- Folder 1. Board Meeting Records. 1989.
- Folder 2. Board Meeting Records. 1990.
- Folder 3. Board Meeting Records. 1991.
- Folder 4. Board Meeting Records. 1992.
- Folder 5. Board Meeting Records. 1994.
- Folder 6. Board Meeting Records. 1996.
- Folder 7. Board Meeting Records. 1997.
- Folder 8. Board Meeting Records. 1998.
- Folder 9. Board Meeting Records. 1999.
- Folder 10. Board Meeting Records. 2000.
- Folder 11. Board Meeting Records. 2002.
- Folder 12. Board Meeting Records. 2003.
- Folder 13. Board Meeting Records. 2004.
- Folder 14. Board Meeting Records. 2005.
- Folder 15. Board Meeting Records. 2006.
- Folder 16. Calendar. 2006.
- Folder 17. Newspaper Clippings. 1989-2007.
- Folder 18. Correspondence. 1992.
- Folder 19. Correspondence. 1993.
- Folder 20. Correspondence. 2005-2006.
- Folder 21. Koons, Kenneth. Families and Farms in the Lower-Cumberland Valley of SouthCentral PA.
  Chapters 1 and 2.
- Folder 22. Koons, Kenneth. Families and Farms in the Lower-Cumberland Valley of SouthCentral PA.
  Chapters 3 and 4.
- Folder 23. Koons, Kenneth.
  Chapter 5, Conclusions, and Appendix. Families and Farms in the Lower-Cumberland Valley of SouthCentral PA.
- Folder 24. Master Plan, First Phase.
- Folder 25. Miscellaneous. 2002, 2005, Undated.
  Includes obituary of Charles Phillippi, died 17 March 2005; brochure and guide for Settlers Museum; photograph of Charles Phillippi in costume; invitation to art exhibit by Charles Phillippi at Art Place, Chilhowie, Virginia.
- Folder 26. Prospectus. 1988.
- Folder 27. Report, USDA, Forest Service. 1993.
  Decision Notice and Finding of No Significant Impact.
- Folder 28. Report. Last Year of Tree Growth for Selected Logs within the Phillippi House. 1992.
- Folder 29. Report. My Story: Charles Phillippi.
- Folder 30. Report. The Phillippi Store: a Video Presentation.
- Folder 31. Report. Proposal: Historic Research and Documentation for the 1880 Farm.
- Folder 32. Report. Research Proposal: Environmental and Living Atmosphere of a Frontier Log Cabin.